本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流
更多中日双语字幕，尽在www.kamigami.org 及微博@诸神字幕组
After leaving Kashan Fortress,
Arslan's company was forced apart
カシャーン城塞を出たアルスラーン一行は
when they repeatedly
encountered the Lusitanians,
度重なるルシタニアの猛追の前に分断され
who pursued them relentlessly,
and now, they were all separately
making their way towards Peshawar.
別行動でペシャワールを目指していた
There are soldiers lying in wait everywhere.
至る所に伏兵がいるな
It seems they are highly displeased
with us heading for Peshawar.
我らがペシャワールへ向かうのがよほど気に食わんようじゃ
I am worried about His Highness.
殿下が心配だ　早く合流せねば
We must rejoin him quickly.
These aren't my words
日听&翻译
小伍
sora
兰樱
校对
小江
mam
They're probably our words
If the whole world only had left hands
片源
Rei
时间轴
钦钦&框框
压制
久嘉
Coolkid
Don't be the bastards who hide their right hands
There's nothing beyond this azure
The day I realized that,
I stopped looking up at the sky
And in the bottomless swamp,
look, there's a bottom
In this town that's growing
even more tainted even now
Even if you just tried to breathe the air
You'd end up breathing in the bad stuff, too
And in the bottomless swamp,
look, there's a bottom
In this town that's growing
even more tainted even now
Even if you just tried to breathe the air
You are friend, Baby Dream
Before I knew it, my heart
Was full of things I had to love all the way
Always losing, leaving
Even the unbearable stuff
Because I don't want to live my days
I amenting, unable to keep them safe
You are friend, Baby, Dream
I'll grow even stronger
These aren't my words
But our words
Several dozen men on horseback.
騎兵が数十
The Zot Glan, is it?
ゾット族か
This is the shortcut to Peshawar,
ペシャワールへの近道ゆえ　ヤツらの縄張りを通らざるをえなかったが…
so I had no choice but to
pass through their territory, but...
Now, then...
さて…
Chief, that's him!
族長　あいつです　妙な銀仮面をかぶってるのは
The one wearing the odd silver mask!
Silver mask?
銀仮面
The Zot Clan...
ゾット族…
This is Zot territory.
ここはゾットの縄張りだ
Leave your gold and your swords and be gone.
金と剣を置いて　うせろ
What's the matter?
どうした
A savage like you, not even
recognizable as man nor monkey...
貴様ごとき　猿とも人とも分からぬ蛮人に　なぜ従わねばならぬ
Why should I do as you say?
Y-You bastard!
き…貴様
Father...
おやじ…
Consider it an honor to die at my hands.
俺の手にかかって死ねることを名誉に思え
族長…
We go, too!
俺たちも続け
Damn!
Little girl, what is your name?
小娘　貴様の名は
Alfreed, daughter of the Zot Clan Chief!
"Chief's Daughter, Zot Clan
Alfreed"
ゾット族族長の娘　アルフリード
Alfreed is a name for a
lady of royal or noble lineage.
アルフリードとは王侯貴族の姫君に使われる名だ
I probably ought to punish you in
a way that befits your presumption.
その思い上がりにふさわしい罰を食らわせてやるべきだろうな
やってみるがいいさ
You just try it.
You bastard!
てめぇ
You move well.
よく動く
But it seems the same
could not be said for your men.
だが　貴様の手下どもはそうはいかなかったようだ
This is what happens when mere bandits
盗賊ごときが王の歩む道を妨げようとするからだ
attempt to stand in the way of a king.
Die.
死ね
なっ
That inept painter I met in the Royal Capital.
王都で出会ったへぼ画家か
Have you wandered all the way to the
borderlands, unable to make a living?
食うに困って　辺境の地まで流れてきたか
Keeping you company seems to take me
お主につきあっていると　人外境に近づいているようで　困ったものよ
closer to uninhabited lands
and I find it to be a problem.
Where is Arslan?
アルスラーンはどこだ
If you die, I would not mind telling you.
お主が死んだら　教えてさしあげてもいいが
Can you do it?
できるか
Well, let us say I will endeavor to do so.
まあ　努力してみるとしようか
Stay out of this!
手を出すな
He killed my father and my friends!
こいつはおやじと仲間の敵だ　私が倒す
I will take him down!
You do not even have a sword.
お主　剣も持っていないではないか
Then lend me yours!
じゃあ　あんたの剣をお貸しよ
I would not mind lending it
to you, but what of collateral?
貸してもよいが　担保はどうする
A girl is nobly trying to avenge her father
親の敵を討とうっていうけなげな女の子から担保を取るっていうの
and you want collateral from her?!
It is our first time meeting, after all.
初対面だからな　安全第一を取りたいわけさ
I wish to be safe rather than sorry.
You're a miser.
しみったれだね
The ladies won't favor you.
女にモテないよ
And besides, you are not capable
第一　お主では　そこの銀仮面の君には勝てんよ
of winning against the
man in the silver mask there.
You would only needlessly shed your blood.
無駄な血を流すだけだ
That's not...!
そんなこと
' Stay back.
下がっていろ
And so ends the farce...
茶番は終わったか
I knew it, but he is strong!
やはり　強い
It should be soon...
そろそろか
lnept painter...
へぼ画家…　いや　ナルサス
No, Narsus.
Oh-ho? You did me the
favor of remembering me?
ほう　覚えていてくれたのか
I know of your great ingenuity.
お前の知略は知っている　殺すには惜しい
It would be a shame to kill you.
Bend the knee and serve me.
膝を屈し　俺に仕えろ
What is so funny?
何がおかしい
Your skill with the sword
knows no equal in this land,
お主の剣技は一国に冠絶するが
but your caliber is lacking for a man
whom I must honor as my liege.
器量においては　主と仰ぐには物足りんな
What?
何
Prince Arslan never gave me such
high-handed orders as "serve me."
アルスラーン殿下は私に　仕えろなどと　頭ごなしに命令はなさらなかった
Why you...
貴様…
You won't get away!
逃がすか
Lord Silver Mask!
銀仮面卿
Are you all right?!
ご無事ですか
He got away from you.
逃げられましたな
That damn masked man!
あの仮面男　次会ったら　絶対に殺してやる
I'll kill him, without fail,
the next time I see him!
You bore it well.
よく我慢したな
お主が逆上して銀仮面に襲いかかっていたら
Had you gone wild with rage
and attacked Silver Mask,
we may not have escaped.
逃げられなかったかもしれん
If I don't live...
生きないと　おやじとみんなの敵　討てないから…
...I won't be able to avenge
my father and everyone else, so...
True enough.
そうだな
Father... Everyone...
おやじ…　みんな…
A dauntless Zot shouldn't be crying, right?
勇猛なゾット族が泣いてちゃダメだよね
Thank you.
ありがとう
I did nothing.
俺は何もしとらんよ
You saved me from that Silver Mask.
助けてもらった　あの銀仮面から
So, thank you.
だから…　ありがとう
You're nicer than I thought.
あんた　意外にいいヤツだね
Than you thought, huh?
意外に…　か
Come to think of it, I hadn't asked your name.
そういえば　あんたの名前　聞いてなかった
What is it?
なんていうの
I am Narsus.
ナルサスだ
Narsus...
ナルサスか
私はアルフリード　よろしく
I am Alfreed. Nice to meet you.
ああ
Yes.
But that rockslide earlier
was a lucky coincidence.
それにしても　さっきは偶然　落石が起こってよかったね
It would've been chancy if it weren't for that.
あれがなかったら　危なかった
That was no coincidence.
偶然ではないさ　ああなるように仕掛けておいたからな
For I had engineered it to happen that way.
What?
You caused that rockslide?
あの落石はナルサスが起こしたの　妖術か何か
With magic or something?
I can manage that much,
even without using magic.
妖術を使わずとも　あのくらいなことはできる
With a leather thong and a piece of wood.
革ひもと木片を使ってな
An application of the principle of the lever.
てこの原理の応用だ
The lever?
てこ
Yes.
そう
The force created by the leather thong
applies torque to the piece of wood
革ひもを使って発生させた力が　木片の回転力となって　その力で…
--and that force...
--I don't really understand, but...
よく分かんないけど…
You're smart, huh?
ナルサスって　頭いいんだね　剣の腕前もすごいし
And your skill with the
sword is incredible, too.
This is what happens when mere bandits
盗賊ごときが王の歩む道を妨げようとするからだ
attempt to stand in the way of a king.
Say, Narsus.
ねえ　ナルサス
How old are you?
あんた　年はいくつなの
Twenty-six, but what of it?
２６だが
Wow, so you're over twenty-five?
I thought you were a little younger.
２５を越してるのか　もう少し若いのかと思ってた
Pardon me for not living
up to your expectations.
ご期待に背いて悪かった
Well, that's all right.
まあ　いいや
There's exactly ten years between us,
so it's easy to remember,
ちょうど私と１０歳違いだから　覚えやすいし
and someone that's a bit
older is more dependable anyway.
年は少し離れてた方が　頼りがいあるものね
All right! I've made up my mind!
よし　決めた
I'm coming with you!
私　ナルサスについていくよ
You have other fellow
Zot Clan members, do you not?
他にも　ゾット族の仲間はいるだろう　戻らなくていいのか
Do you not need to return to them?
No, I don't!
いいの
One month since the Royal-Capital fell.
"The Royal Capital of Ecbatana"
王都陥落よりひと月　ルシタニア内には　３つの力が並立していた
Within Lusitania, there were
three in power with equal authority.
Archpriest Bodin, with the
Temple Knights under his command.
聖騎士団を率いる大司祭ボダン
軍と大臣たちに絶大な支持を得る王弟ギスカール
The royal younger brother, Guiscard,
who had the full support
of the army and the ministers.
And the King, lnnocentis VII,
敵国の王妃に心を奪われ　臣下の信頼を失った国王イノケンティス七世
who had lost the trust of his subjects,
having fallen for the enemy's queen.
As dissension grew deeper by
the moment between these factions,
各勢力の確執が刻一刻と深まるなか　一つの事件が起こった
one incident occurred.
聖騎士団団長ヒルディゴが暗殺されたのである
Hildigo, Commander of the
Temple Knights, was assassinated.
見損なったぞ　国王
I misjudged you, King!
汚れた背教者め
You filthy apostate!
You are going straight to Hell!
貴様の行く末は地獄のみじゃ
ボ…ボダン　何を言っておるのだ
B-Bodin?
What is this you speak of?
You killed Hildigo because of
the opposition to your marriage!
結婚に反対されているからと　ヒルディゴを殺したのだろうが
待て　予はそのような…
--Wait, I never...
--l have no use for your excuses!
言い訳など無用
The King has grown depraved
and this kingdom has been cursed!
王は堕落し　この国は呪われた
神の鉄鎚が下るぞ
God will surely smite you!
M-My little brother, Bodin is
under some sort of misapprehension.
お…弟よ
ボダンは何か勘違いしておる　予のために説明してくれ
Please explain it to him on my behalf.
Are you aware, Lord Archpriest?
大司祭殿はご存じかな
聖騎士団団長が殺されたとき　一人ではなかったことを
That when the Commander
of the Temple Knights was killed,
he was not alone?
What?
何
彼は異教徒の女と床を共にしていたのだ
He was sharing his bed with a heathen woman.
Wh-What slander against a man of the cloth!
せ…聖職者に対して　なんという誹謗を　冒とくの極みじゃぞ
That is blasphemy of the highest order!
冒とくとは　騎士団長にこそ向けられるべき言葉であろう
Blasphemy is the accusation
that ought to be levied against
the Knights' Commander!
聖職者でもある聖騎士団の　しかもその長たる者が
The Temple Knights are also men
of the cloth and for their leader, no less,
to have been doing
who-knows-what with a heathen woman...
異教徒の女と　何をしていたのか
彼の死は神罰であろう
His death was surely divine retribution.
After stirring up such a scandal,
このような不祥事を起こしては
今後　誰もあなたの言葉に耳を傾けますまいな
I doubt anyone will lend an
ear to your words from now on.
You did this, Guiscard!
謀ったな　ギスカール
By the bye...
ところで…
With regards to the banner
of the Faith of Yaldabaoth...
イアルダボート教の御旗ですが
We have taken the liberty
of temporarily taking it down.
我々が　一時　回収させていただきました
--What?!
--My apologies for informing
you only after the fact.
なんじゃと
事後報告となり　申し訳ございませぬ
Why you!
貴様
団長を失い　聖職者としての権威は剥がれ
They have lost their commander,
they have been stripped of
their reputation as men of the cloth,
更に　神の御旗という教会権力の象徴も失った
and furthermore, they have
even lost the divine banner
that is their symbol of the church's authority.
今や　聖騎士団など　雑兵の寄せ集めにすぎん
The Temple Knights are now no more
than a motley crew of common soldiers.
地獄へ落ちろ　悪魔め
Go to Hell, you damn devil!
Prince Guiscard,
ギスカール様
Bodin has departed Ecbatana,
taking the Temple Knights with him.
ボダンが聖騎士団を率いて　エクバターナを離れました
So, that rids us of one inconvenience.
これで　邪魔が一つ消えたか
It seems they headed for Maryam.
ヤツら　マルヤムへ向かったようです
ペシャワールも間もなくです　殿下
We will be at Peshawar shortly, Your Highness.
お疲れでしょうが　もうしばし我慢ください
You must be tired, but please
bear with it for just a while longer.
Yes, I am fine.
大丈夫だ
But this is the farthest
I have come in my entire life.
しかし　これほど遠くまで来たのは　生まれて初めてだ
私が知らない土地も　まだまだあるのだろうな
There must still be many more
lands that are unfamiliar to me...
Has Your Highness heard of the
legendary cities far to the southwest?
殿下はご存じですか
西南の果てにある伝説の都市のことを
伝説の都市
The legendary cities?
Far to the southwest of Pars,
there is a vast desert of nothing
パルス国のはるか西南には　虚無の砂漠が広がり
その向こうには　伝説にのみ語られる青銅都市や円柱都市があると
and beyond it are the
City of Bronze and City of Pillars,
which are only spoken of in legends.
To think that such places exist!
そのようなものが…
When I become a man,
I hope to visit those places
私は大人になったら　そこを訪れ
and study the lost histories and legends.
失われた歴史や伝説を学びたいと思っています
それがエラムの夢か
So, that is your dream?
はい
Yes.
Then, when you have investigated
these histories and legends someday,
では　いずれエラムが調べた歴史や伝説を私にも教えてくれ
share them with me as well.
Even now, I cannot wait to
hear the stories that you will tell.
エラムからどんな話を聞けるのか　今から楽しみだ
If that is Your Highness's wish.
殿下がお望みなら
ぜひ頼む
I would like that very much.
かしこまりました
Very well, Your Highness.
You seem to have grown awfully
friendly with His Highness, Elam.
殿下と随分　仲よくなったようだな　エラム
l-lt was nothing of the...
そ…そのようなことは
Your Highness, we can see it now.
殿下　見えましたよ
That is Peshawar.
あれがペシャワールです
馬を降りて　許しを請…
Get off your horse and beg for...
口数の多い男は好かぬ
I dislike garrulous men.
手を出すな
Do not interfere.
そいつは俺の獲物だ
He is my quarry!
追ってきたのか
So, he came after me.
Quite the tenacious will that one has.
大した執念じゃ
今日こそ　貴様の首を取り　父の無念を晴らす
Today is the day I take your head
"Follower of Lord Silver Mask
Xandes"
and avenge my father!
The fault lies with your
lord father in the first place,
そもそも　お主の父上が
ルシタニア人どもの手先となって　国を売ったがゆえのことであろう
for becoming a pawn for the Lusitanians
and betraying the kingdom.
Do not give me that rubbish!
ふざけるな
王位を奪ったアンドラゴラスなど仕えるに値せんというだけだ
Andragoras stole the throne
and was not deserving
of our service, that is all!
我らは　より王たるにふさわしいお人に
We serve a man who is
more worthy of the crown...
We serve the rightful king of Pars!
パルスの正統の王に仕えているのだ
The rightful king?
正統の王
気付いたか　惜しい
You noticed... Too bad.
Wha?!
なっ
Earth travel magic?
地行術か
貴様は
You are?
One who serves the same master as you.
あなたと主を同じくする者
I am here to aid you, Lord Xandes.
力を貸しますぞ　ザンデ殿
勝手にしろ
Do as you like.
厄介じゃな
This will be troublesome.
なんだ　あれは
What is that?
Sorcery.
魔道の術じゃ
敵め　あのような輩を飼っておったとはな
To think the cursed enemy had
the likes of him in their arsenal.
You bastards, who serve the son of a usurper,
簒奪者の子に仕える貴様らは逆賊にすぎん
are nothing more than traitors!
We are the true loyal subjects of Pars!
我らこそ　真のパルスの忠臣だ
簒奪者の子だと
The son of a usurper, you say?!
Whoever this master is whom you serve,
お前らの主が何者であろうと
whatever His Highness's
origins are, it does not matter!
殿下の出自がどうであろうと関係ない
It is my intent to protect him and...
俺はあの方を守ろうと…
I have you!
取った
Daryun!
ダリューン
無事か　ダリューン
Are you all right, Daryun?!
殿下　地面を
Your Highness, the ground!
殿下
Your Highness!
Elam!
エラム
よそ見を…
Looking away...
殿下を傷つけはさせん
I will not let you harm His Highness!
Daryun!
ダリューン
見苦しい
Disgraceful.
Your Highness.
殿下…
申し訳ございません
I cannot even find the words to apologize!
To have placed Your Highness in danger...
殿下を危険にさらしてしまうとは
大丈夫だ　ケガはない
It is fine. I am unhurt.
I owe it to Elam.
エラムのおかげだ
ありがとう
Thank you.
Oh... uh, not at all.
あっ…　いえ
You are always coming to my aid, Daryun.
いつも　ダリューンに助けられているのだ
たまには　私がダリューンを助けてもいいではないか
Should I come to your aid once
in a while, what is wrong with that?
ところで　ギーヴは
By the bye, where is Gieve?
Oh, Mistress Farangis!
ファランギース殿
I, Gieve, spent many a
sleepless night with worry.
心配で　このギーヴ　眠れぬ日々を過ごしておりました
ファランギース殿も　きっと　同じ気持ちでいらしたのでは
Surely, you must have felt
the same, Mistress Farangis?
I did not worry whatsoever.
心配など　まったくしておらぬ
For you are the sort of man likely to survive,
天上の神々をだましてでも　生き残りそうな男じゃからな
even if it means cheating
the gods of the heavens.
If it is to see you, Mistress Farangis,
ファランギース殿と会うためなら　天上の神々をもだましてみせましょうぞ
I would even cheat the gods of the heavens!
I am glad we were able to come together again.
合流できてよかった
It is really not the same
when you are not by my side.
やはり　私のそばには　お主がいなくては
ありがたいお言葉です　殿下
I am grateful that you
would say so, Your Highness.
Mm.
王位など関係ない
The throne does not matter.
It is for the sake of this man himself
俺は　この方自身のために　剣を振るい続けるのだ
that I will continue to wield my sword.
The azure crescent moon
wheels across the night sky
The glittering world transcends the clouds
With this journey's beginning that you dance now
Off into the yonder wishes go, drifting
When a tale that is shapeless
Spreads across the moonlight
The treasure that is within you
Melts away into the wind now
Tomorrow, try to take
wing as your unvarnished self
Sometime, somewhere,
you wanted this, remember?
You can hear it, can't you?
There; that shining dream from that day
The azure crescent moon
wheels across the night sky
The glittering world transcends the clouds
With this journey's beginning that you dance now
Off into the yonder wishes go
Oh, 'til this dream comes to an end
銀仮面の両目に　毒煙が燃え上がり
The venom flared in Silver Mask's eyes
それが　アルスラーンに向かって　音もなく吹きつけてきた
and without a sound, it shot towards Arslan.
次回　王子二人
Next time, "Two Princes."
"Chapter XIII
Two Princes"
少年は　そして王となる
And thus, the boy would become king.